(upbeat music)
- Hello, English learners.
Welcome back to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today we're swimming.
- That's right.
- A nice summertime lesson for everyone.
- Summertime lesson.
- So we're gonna be talking about swimming
and well, it's a very popular sport, right?
- Yeah, so this is another
lesson in our sports series.
- And our sports series, okay.
So why don't we preview
some of the language
we'll find in the dialogue?
- Very cablery preview.
- All right, we have two
words to look at here.
The first word is sailing.
- Sailing.
Well, this is the verb to sail, right?
- Mm-hmm.
- So sailing is traveling in a boat.
- In a boat with no engine.
- Right, so you must use
the wind to push you forward.
- Exactly, that's a sailboat.
- Yes.
- Okay, so sailing.
Now let's take a look at
our other word, anchor.
- Another boat word here, anchor.
- Anchor.
- Now it's spelled A-N-C-H-O-R.
- Right.
- But you don't pronounce the
C-H as you normally would, right?
- Another one of these really
difficult to spell English words.
- Right, so you don't say
anchor, you would say anchor.
- Anchor.
- So the anchor is a verb and noun.
- That's right.
Well, when anchor is used as a noun, it
means the hook that you throw over the boat
into the water and it keeps
you staying in the same place.
- Okay, but the verb to anchor.
- Yes.
- What does it mean?
- To do that.
- To do that, right?
- So to throw the anchor into the water,
you would just say to anchor the boat.
- Exactly, to keep it in the same place.
- Okay, great words related to sailing.
But now let's listen to our
dialogue for the first time.
What's happening here, Erica?
- Well, we've got two
friends here who are sailing
in their boat and they
decide to take a swim.
- Mm, let's see what happens.
(upbeat music)
- This is such a beautiful day.
- Great day for sailing.
- It sure is, the water looks so nice.
Anchor the boat for a little while.
I'm gonna take a bit.
Why are you doggy paddling?
I taught you how to swim.
Do your breast stroke.
- I get too tired.
I'll just back stroke, it's easier.
- Try kicking your legs more.
That's good, don't go out too far.
- It's fine, jump in.
- Kathy, get back here.
I see a shark.
- Ah, how big, how big,
how big the boat closer.
- The shark is coming straight towards me.
- It's right under you.
Kathy!
- All right, so a shark attack.
- I know, this is my worst
fear when swimming.
- Really in the ocean, right?
- Yeah, well, also in the
lake, but no sharks in lakes.
- I know, but I'm still afraid of them.
- All right, so don't worry about it.
I'm sure the girl is okay.
It's probably not a shark.
Maybe it's a dolphin.
- Yeah, or maybe she's
gonna punch the shark
in the face and she'll escape.
- Okay, let's take a look at some of the
words that we saw in language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
- We have three excellent
swimming words for you.
The first one is doggy paddling.
- Doggy paddling.
- So doggy paddling, it's not really
a proper way of swimming, right?
- No, you don't see this in the Olympics.
- So if you've ever seen a dog swim,
that's why they call it doggy paddling.
- Right, you're sort of moving
your hands quickly in front of you.
- And your legs are all over the place.
And you're basically not really swimming.
You're just trying to stay afloat.
You're trying not to drown.
- Trying not to sink.
- Yeah, okay, so doggy paddling.
- Again, this can be a noun or a verb.
The doggy paddle, this swimming
style or doggy paddling, the verb.
- Okay, interesting.
All right, let's take a look at
our second swimming style.
- Breaststroke.
- The breaststroke.
How is this one?
- Well, it's sort of like
swimming like a frog.
- So you have your legs that
are similar to like a frog, right?
And what are your hands doing?
- Your hands are moving in front of
you together then out towards the side.
- Okay, so you're kind of doing circles.
- Yeah, half circles.
- Half circles.
- Okay, breaststroke.
- Yeah.
- But you get kind of tired
when you swim like this, right?
- Yeah, maybe.
- Yeah, yeah.
Now, let's take a look at our third word.
Backstroke.
- Backstroke.
So this one's pretty easy.
Backstroke you are.
- Lying on your back.
- You're lying on your back.
- In the water.
- And your, can your feet as well.
- Yep.
- But what are your hands doing?
- They're going back behind you.
See, I'm doing it now.
- See?
- All right, if you guys
could be here in the
studio, you would see
Erica doing her backstroke.
- Yeah, I'm pretty good at it.
- Yeah.
Okay, so let's listen
to this dialogue again
and then we'll come back
and look at some great phrases.
(upbeat music)
- This is such a beautiful day.
- Great day for sailing.
- It sure is the water looks so nice.
Anchor the boat for a little while.
- I'm going to take a dip.
- Why are you doggy paddling?
I taught you how to swim.
Do your breaststroke.
- I get too tired.
I'll just backstroke.
It's easier.
- Try kicking your legs more.
That's good.
Don't go out too far.
- It's fine.
Jump in.
- Kathy, get back here.
I see a shark.
(screaming)
Help me help bring the boat closer.
The shark is coming straight towards me.
- It's right under you.
Kathy.
(upbeat music)
- Okay, so we have some really good
phrases related to swimming and water.
- Yeah.
- Okay, let's take a look
at these in fluency builder.
- Fluency builder.
- All right, the first one.
I love this phrase, take a dip.
Take a dip.
So if I say I'm going to take a dip.
- You're going to have a quick swim.
- A quick swim.
So you can take a dip in the pool.
- Yep.
- In the lake.
- In the ocean.
- Even in your bathtub, right?
- No.
- No, it's just for swimming.
Unless your bathtub is
really, really, really big.
- All right, so not for the
bathtub, but for swimming.
- Yep.
- Okay, now let's take a
look at our second phrase.
For a little while.
- For a little while.
- This is really common.
I use this a lot.
- Yeah, me too.
I probably use it 500 times a day.
- Okay, so let's listen
to some examples with
for a little while and then
we'll come back and explain it.
- Example one.
- I'm tired.
I'm just going to sit
down for a little while.
- Example two.
- It will only hurt for a little while.
- Example three.
- Do you want to play
tennis for a little while?
- So it means for a short time.
- For a short time and
you can change it, right?
You can say, oh, I'm going
to play for a little while.
- Yeah.
- Or I'm going to sleep for
a little while for a short time.
- Yep.
- All right, so if learners use this phrase,
I find it sounds really, really great
'cause it's not something
that students normally use.
- Yeah, I guess a student wouldn't
really use this phrase normally.
- Yeah, so guys use it
'cause you'll sound awesome.
- Yeah, you'll sound really, really fluent.
Okay, and let's take a
look at our last phrase.
Straight towards.
- Straight towards.
- Straight towards me.
- Okay, so straight means directly.
- Right, in a line.
- In a line, not going
anywhere else, but directly.
- Not moving side to side
and towards is in that direction.
- Mm-hmm, so the shark was
coming straight towards me.
It's coming directly at me.
- Moving in a line and
not moving side to side.
- Okay, so can you give me another example
of how you would use straight towards?
- Watch out, there's a car
coming straight towards you.
- Okay, directly towards you.
- Yeah, or maybe when I get home from
work, I go straight towards the fridge.
- Really?
- Yes.
- I believe this.
- All right, so straight towards directly.
- Okay, so we've looked at a lot
of great words, really good phrases.
Let's listen to this dialogue one
last time, and then we'll come back,
and Eric is gonna tell us a
really great story about voting.
(upbeat music)
- This is such a beautiful day.
- Great day for sailing.
- It sure is, the water looks so nice.
Anchor the boat for a little while.
I'm gonna take a dip.
(upbeat music)
- Why are you doggy paddling?
I tell you how to swim,
do your breast stroke.
- I get too tired.
I'll just back stroke, it's easier.
- Drag kicking your legs more.
That's good, don't go out too far.
- It's fine, jump in.
- Kathy, get back here, I see a shark.
(screaming)
- Hey, help, bring the boat closer.
The shark is coming straight towards me.
- It's right under you, Kathy.
(upbeat music)
- All right, well, Marco, I was telling you
that I used to spend
every summer on the lake,
and my family had a
really small house on a small
island, and my cousins
had another small house
on another small island, so
our families are really close,
and we used to go to one
house for dinner one night,
and the other house
didn't earth the next night.
So everyone was over at my cousin's house,
except for my grandfather,
and so he was thinking,
"Okay, it's late, maybe I
better go pick up my wife
and see what's going on,"
so he goes into the boat.
It's dark, there's no light on the boat.
He's driving straight towards
the island, when suddenly my
cousin, in his boat, drives
directly into my grandfather.
- So they crashed, they crashed.
- Two boats crashed in the lake.
- And then my grandfather's
boat flipped over,
turned upside down,
and he fell in the water.
- But he was okay, right?
- Yeah, he was okay, but he
was really angry about this,
and the boat stayed in the water,
and the engine fell down to the bottom.
So we had to go the next
morning to get the boat,
and we actually had to
hire some scuba divers
to go to the bottom of
the lake to get the engine.
- Wow.
- Yeah.
- I imagine your grandpa was pretty angry.
- Yeah, he tells the story every year.
- Exactly, but you know what?
I've got a million of
these crazy lake stories,
'cause my family--
- It always happens.
- Yeah.
- All right, guys, well, do
you have any crazy stories,
or any stories
related to boats, or to
swimming, or to shark
attack, or shark attacks?
- Yeah.
- So come to our website,
www.EnglishPod.com.
Leave your stories, share with us, and
also if you have any doubts or questions.
Erica and I are always there to answer.
- Well, we're out of time for this
lesson, but until next time, bye.
(upbeat music)